I was one of the only kids in college who had a reason
لقد كنت واحدة من الأشخاص في الكلية ممن كان لديهم سبب
to go to the P.O. box at the end of the day,
للذهاب إلى صندوق البريد في نهاية اليوم
and that was mainly because my mother has never believed
والسبب الرئيسي في ذلك يعود إلى أن والدتي لا تؤمن أبداً
in email, in Facebook, in texting or cell phones in general.
في البريد الإلكتروني، والفيسبوك، ولا الرسائل القصيرة أو الهواتف الخليوية بشكل عام
And so while other kids were BBM-ing their parents,
وذلك في الوقت الذي كان فيه الأطفال الآخرون يراسلون آبائهم من خلال البلاك بيري
I was literally waiting by the mailbox
أنا كنت أنتظر بقرب صندوق البريد
to get a letter from home to see how the weekend had gone,
للحصول على رسالة من أهلي لأعلم كيف قضوا عطلة نهاية الأسبوع
which was a little frustrating when Grandma was in the hospital,
والذي من شأنه أن سبب لي بعض الإحباط عندما كانت جدتي في المستشفى
but I was just looking for some sort of scribble,
لكنني كنت أتطلع نوعا ما إلى خربشات
some unkempt cursive from my mother.
بعض ما تخطه أمي بطريقة غير منظمة
And so when I moved to New York City after college
ولذلك حين انتقلت إلى مدينة نيويورك بعد الجامعة
and got completely sucker-punched in the face by depression,
وبعد أن شعرت وكأنني تلقيت لكمة على وجهي بسبب الإحباط
I did the only thing I could think of at the time.
قمت بالشيء الوحيد الذي استطعت التفكير فيه ذلك الوقت
I wrote those same kinds of letters that my mother had written me
قمت بكتابة رسائل مماثلة لتلك التي كانت أمي تكتبها لي
for strangers, and tucked them all throughout the city,
لأنشخاص غرباء، ثم قمت بدسها جميعها في أنحاء المدينة
dozens and dozens of them. I left them everywhere,
عشرات العشرات من الرسائل وقمت بتركها في كل مكان
in cafes and in libraries, at the U.N., everywhere.
في المقاهي والمكتبات، ومباني الأمم المتحدة، وفي كل مكان
I blogged about those letters and the days
قمت بعمل مدونات لتحدث عن هذه الرسائل والأيام
when they were necessary, and I posed
التي كانت مهمة فيها، وطرحت
a kind of crazy promise to the Internet:
وعداً مجنوناً على شبكة الانترنت
that if you asked me for a hand-written letter,
والذي كان "إذا طلبت مني رسالة مكتوبة بخط اليد،
I would write you one, no questions asked.
سأقوم بكتابتها لك، بدون طرح أسئلة.
Overnight, my inbox morphed into this harbor of heartbreak --
وفي ليلة وضحاها، كان صندوق الوارد لدي قد تحول إلى عبارة عن ملاذ للحسرات
a single mother in Sacramento, a girl being bullied
أم وحيدة في ساكرامينتو، فتاة تعرضت لمعاملة قاسية
in rural Kansas, all asking me, a 22-year-old girl
في ريف كانساس، جميعهم طلبوا مني، فتاة في الثانية والعشرين من عمرها
who barely even knew her own coffee order,
والتي بالكاد تعرف شيئاً عن الحياة،
to write them a love letter and give them a reason
أن أكتب رسالة محبة لهم، وإعطائهم سبباً
to wait by the mailbox.
للانتظار لدى صندوق البريد
Well, today I fuel a global organization
حسنا، اليوم أصبحت أنا مصدر إلهام لمنظمة عالمية
that is fueled by those trips to the mailbox,
والتي كان السبب الرئيسي لإلهامها تلك الرحلات الى البريد
fueled by the ways in which we can harness social media
والتي تم تغذيتها بطرق تمكننا من تسخير وسائل الإعلام الإجتماعية
like never before to write and mail strangers letters
كما لم يسبق لها أن كانت لكتابة رسائل ومراسلة غرباء
when they need them most, but most of all,
عندما كانوا في أشد الحاجة لها، ولكن معظمهم
fueled by crates of mail like this one, my trusty mail crate,
تم إلهامهم عن طريق صناديق البريد مثل هذا الصندوق، صندوقي البريدي المؤتمن
filled with the scriptings of ordinary people,
الممتلئ بكتابات لأناس عاديين
strangers writing letters to other strangers not because
غرباء يكتبون رسائل لغرباء آخرين، وذلك ليس لأنهم
they're ever going to meet and laugh over a cup of coffee,
سيلتقون ويتبادلون الضحك وفنجان قهوة
but because they have found one another by way of letter-writing.
ولكن لأنه التقى أحدهم الآخر عن طريق كتابة رسالة
But, you know, the thing that always gets me
لكن، أتعلمون الأمرالذي كان دائما يتملكني
about these letters is that most of them have been written
في هذه الرسائل، أن معظمها قد كتبت
by people that have never known themselves loved on a piece of paper.
من أشخاص، لم يسبق لهم أن عرفوا في حياتهم أنهم قد أحبوا على قطعة ورق
They could not tell you about the ink of their own love letters.
لم يكن بإمكانهم الإفصاح عن من خلال حبر رسائلهم الغرامية
They're the ones from my generation,
هؤلاء الأشخاص هم من جيلي
the ones of us that have grown up into a world
هذا الجيل الذي ترعرع في عالم
where everything is paperless, and where some
حيث لا وجود للورق، وحيث
of our best conversations have happened upon a screen.
تحدث أفضل حواراتنا أمام شاشة
We have learned to diary our pain onto Facebook,
فقد تعلمنا بأن نقوم بتدوين مذكراتنا اليومية وآلامنا على الفيسبوك
and we speak swiftly in 140 characters or less.
وأن نتكلم بسرعة باستخدام 140 حرفاً أو أقل
But what if it's not about efficiency this time?
لكن ماذا لو لم نكن نتحدث عن الكفاءة هذه المرة؟
I was on the subway yesterday with this mail crate,
في الأمس كنت في نفق القطار ممسكة بصندوق البريد هذا
which is a conversation starter, let me tell you.
والذي يعد مطلِقاً للمحادثة، اسمحوا لي أن أخبركم
If you ever need one, just carry one of these. (Laughter)
إذا احتجت يوما لذلك، ما عليك إلا أن تحمل واحدا كهذا(ضحك)
And a man just stared at me, and he was like,
وكان رجل يحدق بي، وكأنه يقول لي
"Well, why don't you use the Internet?"
"حسناً، لماذا لا تستخدمين شبكة الانترنت؟"
And I thought, "Well, sir, I am not a strategist,
عندها رددت عليه في نفسي "حسنا، سيدي أنا لست خبيرة استراتيجية،
nor am I specialist. I am merely a storyteller."
ولا متخصصة، أنا مجرد راوية قصص."
And so I could tell you about a woman
و يمكنني إخباركم عن امرأة
whose husband has just come home from Afghanistan,
كان زوجها قد عاد من أفغانستان
and she is having a hard time unearthing this thing called conversation,
حينها كانت تمر عليها أوقات عصيبة تبحث بها عن شيء يدعى حوار،
and so she tucks love letters throughout the house
وبذلك قامت بدس رسائل غرامية في أرجاء المنزل
as a way to say, "Come back to me.
وكأنها تقول "هيا، عد لي
Find me when you can."
جدني حين تتمكن من ذلك"
Or a girl who decides that she is going to leave love letters
أو قصة فتاة قررت أن تترك رسائل غرامية
around her campus in Dubuque, Iowa, only to find
حول الحرم الجامعي في دوبوك، ايوا، لتجد بعدها
her efforts ripple-effected the next day when she walks out
جهودها تلك قد انتشر أثرها في اليوم التالي، حين كانت تمشي
onto the quad and finds love letters hanging
في ساحة الكلية ووجدت رسائل غرامية متدلية
from the trees, tucked in the bushes and the benches.
من الأشجار، تم دسها بين الشجيرات والمقاعد الخشبية
Or the man who decides that he is going to take his life,
أو كالرجل الذي قرر إنهاء حياته
uses Facebook as a way to say goodbye
واستخدام الفيسبوك كوسيلة ليودع
to friends and family.
أصدقائه وعائلته.
Well, tonight he sleeps safely with a stack of letters
حسنا، هو الآن بخير ينام مع كومة من الرسائل
just like this one tucked beneath his pillow,
كتلك التي تم تخبئتها تحت وسادته
scripted by strangers who were there for him when.
والتي خُطت من قبل غرباء كانوا هنالك إلى جانبه
These are the kinds of stories that convinced me
هذه القصص هي التي جعلتني أؤمن
that letter-writing will never again need to flip back her hair
بأن كتابة الرسائل لم تعد بحاجة للاستعراض
and talk about efficiency, because she is an art form now,
والتحدث عن الكفاءة ، لأنها هي بحد ذاتها أصبحت شكلاً من أشكال الفن الآن
all the parts of her, the signing, the scripting, the mailing,
بكل أشكالها، التوقيع، الكتابة، المراسلة
the doodles in the margins.
الرسومات على الهوامش
The mere fact that somebody would even just sit down,
ومجرد فكرة جلوس شخص ما
pull out a piece of paper and think about someone
ليمسك بقطعة ورق والتفكير في شخص آخر
the whole way through, with an intention that is so much
بشكل كامل، مع وجود مقصد لذلك
harder to unearth when the browser is up and the iPhone
يصعب إظهاره في الوقت الذي يكون فيه محرك البحث يعمل، والآيفون
is pinging and we've got six conversations rolling in at once,
يرن مع وجود ستة محادثات في الوقت ذاته
that is an art form
هو بحد ذاته فن
that does not fall down to the Goliath of "get faster,"
والذي لا يأبه لمسألة " لنسرع"
no matter how many social networks we might join.
بغض النظر عن عدد المواقع الإجتماعية المشتركين بها
We still clutch close these letters to our chest,
فإننا ما زلنا نقوم بضم هذه الرسائل إلى صدورنا
to the words that speak louder than loud,
إلى الكلمات التي تتكلم بصوت أعلى
when we turn pages into palettes to say the things
وذلك حين نقوم بتحويل هذه الأوراق إلى لوحات للبوح
that we have needed to say,
بالأشياء التي طالما احسسنا بحاجة إلى قولها
the words that we have needed to write, to sisters
البوح بالكلمات التي طالما احتجنا كتابتها، لأخواتنا
and brothers and even to strangers, for far too long.
وإخواننا أو حتى للغرباء، منذ فترة طويلة
Thank you. (Applause)
شكراً لكم. (تصفيق)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)